[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So now let's try a little bit larger and compare and see what happens.
حسنًا، لنجرب الآن بشكل أكبر قليلًا ونرى ما سيحدث.
So remember we have our first curve, the blue curve,
تذكر أنه لدينا أول منحنى المنحنى الأزرق،
where eta was 10 to the minus 5.
حيث η كان 10 إلى سالب 5.
Then we have the scion curve where eta was 50% larger so
ثم لدينا المنحنى التابع حيث η كان أكبر بنسبة 50%
10 to 1.5 times 10 to the -5.
لذا 10 إلى 1.5 ضرب 10 إلى -5.
And now we tried even larger parameter.
والآن، قمنا أيضًا بتجربة متغير أكبر.
So this is the red line,
حسنًا، هذا هو الخط الأحمر،
this is eta = 2.5 times 10 to the -5.
هذا η = 2.5 ضرب 10 إلى -5.
So this is 2.5 times bigger than the blue line.
لذلك هذا أكبر 2.5 مرة من الخط الأزرق.
And what we see, we see bigger oscillations in the beginning and
وما نراه، هو أننا نرى ذبذبات أكبر في البداية
the early oscillation phase goes on for a long time.
تدوم مرحلة الذبذبة المبكرة لوقت طويل.
As you see, the oscillations are decreasing towards the end, but
وكما ترى، يتناقص التذبذب نحو النهاية ولكن
decreasing, but we still pick the parameter that is too big.
يتناقص، ولكن ما زلنا نختار المتغير الذي يكون كبيرًا للغاية.
You see the oscillations is not converging.
ترى أن الذبذبات لا تلتقي.
There's a gap, significant gap in the likelihood function,
فهناك فجوة، فجوة كبيرة، في وظيفة الاحتمال،
l of w so the red one, 2.5 times 10 to the -5 is too big.
l الخاصة بـ w، لذلك يكون الخط الأحمر، 2.5 مرة مضروبًا في 10 إلى -5، كبيرًا للغاية.
So let's understand a little better why those oscillations come about.
لنفهم بشكل أفضل سبب حدوث هذه الذبذبات.
So, if I were to use the loose,
لذا إلى كنت سأستخدم حجم الخطوة
very smooth step size, what happens is, I start from the starting point and
المرن السلس للغاية، فما يحدث هو، أنني أبدأ من نقطة البداية
I take these little steps and I'm kind of following this nice smooth curve.
وأخذ هذه الخطوات الصغيرة وأتبع هذا المنحنى السلس إلى حد ما.
All the way to my desired parameter, w hat.
طوال الطريق وصولًا إلى المتغير المرغوب الخاص بي، w hat.
If you pick a step size that is too big,
إذا اخترت حجمًا تدريجيًا كبيرًا للغاية،
I look at a gradient here and it's looking pretty good, a direction in the beginning.
أنا أنظر إلى التدرج هنا وهو يبدو رائعًا للغاية اتجاهًا في البداية.
So let me change colors there just to make it super obvious.
لذا دعني أغير الألوان هناك لجعل الأمر واضح للغاية فحسب.
So I'm going to use
وبالتالي سأستخدم
green to the note that this step size, which is too big, so I start here.
اللون الأخضر لملاحظة حجم الخطوة هذه الكبير للغاية، لذا سأبدأ هنا.
I find the gradient direction but I take a step that's too big.
وأعثر على اتجاه التدرج، ولكن أخذ خطوة كبيرة للغاية.
Boom, I went to somewhere really far away over here so
بوم، ذهبت إلى مكان بعيد للغاية هنا، لذلك
it took an eta that was too big.
أخذ قيمة η التي كانت كبيرة للغاية.
And now I compute the gradient here, and it's in this direction,
والآن أقوم بحساب التدرج هنا، وهو في هذا الاتجاه،
and boom, we took a step size of too big.
وبوم لقد أخذنا حجم خطوة كبير للغاية.
I ended up over here, and then I compute the gradient and
فانتهى بي المطاف هنا، ثم أقوم بحساب التدرج
I get something in this direction and then boom I take a step size that's too big,
وأحصل على شيء في هذا الاتجاه، ثم بوم أخذ حجم خطوة كبير للغاية،
I ended up here and that step size is too big and so on.
انتهى بي الأمر هنا، وهذا الحجم التدريجي كبير للغاية، وهكذا.
And you keep oscillating back and forth these really big steps.
ويتم إجراء التذبذب ذهابًا وإيابًا هذه التدرجات الكبيرة للغاية.
Now in this case, in the red line, 2.5 x 10 to the minus 5.
والآن في هذه الحالة، في الخط الأحمر، 2.5 × 10 إلى -5.
You see this oscillations are decreasing, so
ترى أن هذا التذبذب يتناقص لذا
eventually it's going to get closer and closer to w hat.
وفي نهاية المطاف سيقترب أكثر فأكثر من w hat.
But you have to be careful.
ولكن يجب أن تكون حذرًا.
Now let's see what happens when we pick a eta parameter, they're just too,
الآن دعونا نرى ما سيحدث عندما نقوم باختيار متغير η، ستكون فقط
too, too large.
كبيرة للغاية جدًا.
What I've done here is taken a much bigger parameter, so
ما قمت به هنا، هو أخذ متغير أكبر بكثير، لذلك
I picked a eta, which has a step size 10 to the -4.
اخترت η، التي لديها تدرجات تصل إلى 10 إلى -4.
Remember they're the ones who were over ten to minus five,
تذكر هذه هي من كانت أكثر من عشرة إلى سالب خمسة،
as you can see they're increasing, this is ten to the minus four, so
وكما ترى فهي تتزايد، هذا يكون عشرة إلى سالب أربعة، لذلك
ten times bigger than this blue line here which is eta ten to the minus five.
هي أكبر عشر مرات من الخط الأزرق هذا هنا الذي هو η عشرة إلى سالب خمسة.
First thing they observe is why all the oscillations?
أول ما ستلاحظه هو لما كل هذه الذبذبات؟
This parameter is too big, things are going everywhere,
فهذا المتغير كبير للغاية، تنطلق الأمور في كل مكان
doesn't seem to be converging and the likelihood value is much,
ولا يبدو أنها تتقارب وقيمة الاحتمال أقل بكثير
much lower than of the other parameters.
جدًا من المتغيرات الأخرى.
The other way to look at it is, look, we thought that the difference between
الطريقة الأخرى للنظر إلى هذا هي، أننا اعتقدنا أن الفرق بين
the red parameter, which was, we thought was too big and the blue parameter,
المتغير الأحمر، الذي كان، اعتقدنا أنه كان كبيرًا للغاية وأن المتغير الأزرق،
which was better with the cyan one was a big gap,
الذي كان أفضل مع المتغير باللون الأزرق السماوي الذي كان يمثل فجوة كبيرة،
but look at the gap between, this all curves look really small because we had to
ولكن انظر إلى الفجوة بين، كل هذه المنحنيات تبدو صغيرة للغاية لأنه تعين علينا
make the scale much bigger to show this wildly oscillating one.
جعل المقياس أكبر بكثير لعرض هذا المنحنى المتذبذب بشكل كبير.
So ten to the minus four was too big.
لذا عشرة إلى سالب أربعة كان كبيرًا للغاية.
So here's what I've learned, we've learned that ten to minus six, too small,
حسنًا هذا هو ما تعلمته، لقد تعلمنا أن عشرة إلى سالب ستة، صغير للغاية،
ten to the minus four is too big.
وعشرة إلى سالب أربعة كبير للغاية.
Now, we have a range between the too big and too small, and
ولدينا الآن نطاق بين كبير للغاية وصغير للغاية
we can search in that range.
ويمكننا البحث في هذا النطاق.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]